Jaafar Harabi

Full Stack Developer Djerba, Tunisia 4180 | +216 54091605



<u>jaafar.harabi@enig.u-gabes.tn</u> | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/jaafar-harabi/</u> <u>www.jaafardev.me</u> | <u>www.github.com/jaafar-harabi</u>

Professional summary

I am a passionate Full Stack developer dedicated to creating innovative and efficient solutions. My expertise lies in MERN stack development (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), and I have a strong understanding of cloud computing (AWS, Azure), Git (GitHub), Docker, CI/CD, and responsive design. I am motivated to contribute to the success of ambitious projects.

Skills

Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, SQL

Frameworks and libraries: React, Next.js, Node.js (Express), Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Tools and technologies: Git (GitHub), Docker (Docker Compose), CI/CD, Testing, WordPress, Cloud (AWS,

Azure), Odoo

Education

Chemical-process engineering

2020-2023

National Engineering School of Gabes, Tunisia

Physical-chemistry preparatory class

Erriadh Secondary School, Djerba, Tunisia

2016-2020

The Higher Institute of Applied Sciences and Technology of Gabes, Tunisia

Experimental Science BA

2016

Work experience

Tunisian chemical group, Gabes, Tunisia

02/2023 - 06/2023

Graduation project

- Analyze in detail the existing steam production circuit: analysis, design and implementation of interactive solutions
- Improvement of the energy efficiency of a steam production circuit: study, simulation and proposed modifications
- Create an interactive interface in HTML, CSS and JavaScript (React, D3.js)
- Integrate a MongoDB database to manage critical circuit information

Tunisian chemical group, Gabes, Tunisia

06/2022 - 07/2022

Engineering internship

- Perform a mass and energy balance on a utility unit auxiliary boiler.

Iris Djerba Hotel, Djerba, Tunisia

07/2021 - 07/2023

Web developer (remote / part-time)

- Design and development of web applications using PHP, MySQL, JavaScript and WordPress
- Maintenance and optimization of web applications, bug fixes, performance improvements and new features
- Regular update of the hotel website content.

National Water Exploitation and Distribution Company, Djerba, Tunisia

07/2021 - 08/2021

- Trainee
- Discover the professional environment.
- Develop networks through observation and learning.

Training

Bootcamp Full Stack javascript (MEAN Stack), Technologia academy

02/2023 - 04/2023

Bootcamp Full Stack javascript (MERN Stack), Pingucoder academy

04/2023 - present

Volunteer Experience

Member of the TuniBless e.V. Association 2023 - present Member of the Automatic Electric Club of the National Engineering School of Gabes 2022 - 2023Member of the Process Engineering Club at National Engineering School of Gabes 2020 - 2023 Member of the Friends of the Medina Association Erriadh in Djerba 2017 - 2020

Languages

Arabic: Native language

French: Fluent English: Fluent

German: Intermediate-advanced

Interests

- Chess
- Novel reading